Franz Boas Papers 1862-1942 Mss.B.B61.inventory01
American Philosophical Society
Franz Boas Papers: Inventory (A)
1862-1942
Mss.B.B61.inventory01
American Philosophical Society
1.0 section
This is part of the large inventory for the Franz Boas Papers (Mss B B61). For complete information concerning this collection, please view the Collection Description.
Boas, Franz, 1858-1942
Scope and Contents note
Due to the size of the collection, the content for Series I has been divided into multiple inventories. Please follow the links below to browse the inventories.
Inventories
Correspondents A
Correspondents B
Correspondents C
Correspondents D
Correspondents E-G
Correspondents H
Correspondents I-K
Correspondents L
Correspondents M
Correspondents N-Q
Correspondents R
Correspondents S
Correspondents T-V
Correspondents W-Z
- Franz Boas Papers - Correspondents A
  - A - Z
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 17; 1p.
  - Aall, A. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1926 Sept. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Oct. 12; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Oct. 16; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Nov. 18; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1926 July 22; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Sept. 10; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Feb. 4; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1927 June 3; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1927 Oct. 3; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Sept. 28; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Nov. 1; 2p.
    - A. Einstein -- to A. Aall, Feb. 19, 1927
    - G. Fasting -- to A. Aall, Nov. 20, 1924
  - Aal, H.H. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1924 Oct. 30; 4p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Oct. 22; 4p
    - To Boas, 1925 Dec. 31; 4p
    - To Boas, 1926 Apr. 4; 2p
    - To Boas, 1926 Apr. 22; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1926 Oct. 14; 3p
    - To Boas, 1927 June 5; 4p
    - To Boas, 1927 Dec. 20; 1p
    - From Owen, R.L., 1925 Dec. 4
  - Aall, H.H. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1924 Oct. 13; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Dec. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Dec. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Jan. 22; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 Mar. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1926 May 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 7; 1p.
  - Abbe, Cleveland (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1900 Mar. 3
    - From Boas, 1900 Mar. 9; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1900 Mar. 14; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1900 Mar. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1900 Mar. 13; 2p.
  - Abbes, Heinrich (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1886 Apr. 5
  - Abbott, Arletta M. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1906 Feb. 26; 3p.
    - To Butler, N.M., 1906 Feb. 14; 1p.
  - Abbot, Charles Greeley (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1909 Dec. 15
    - From Boas, 1919 Jan. 2; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 May 5; 4p.
    - From Boas, 1930 Jan. 23; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Apr. 17; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 3; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 8; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1929 May 1; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Jan. 22; 1p.
    - C.G. Abbot -- to U.S. Sec'y of State
      - (enc. with M.W. Stirling, 1930, May 19)
    - C.G. Abbot -- to U.S. Sec'y of State, 1930 May 16; 1p.
    - C.G. Abbot -- from F. White, 1930 June 5
  - Abbott, E. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1925 Jan. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1925 Feb. 10; 1p.
  - Abderhalden, Emil (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1920 May 18; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1936 Nov. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 Jan. 14; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1933 July 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 June 24; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 25; 2p.
  - Abeel, N. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1932 Oct. 31; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Nov. 2; 1p.
  - Abel, J.J. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1923 Jan. 3; 1p.
  - Abrams, R.H. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1934 Aug. 6; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1934 Aug. 8; 1p.
  - Abs, O. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1930 Aug. 13; 1p.
  - Academy of Medicine, New York (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    (see G.C. Brown)
  - Academy of Natural Sciences (Box 1)
    (see James A.G. Rehn)
  - Academy of Sciences of Jerusalem (Box 1)
    - (see F.B. to I. Velokovsky) enc., 1940 Feb. 10
  - Aceredido, P. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1912 July28; 1p.
  - Acevedo, Felix (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1912 Mar. 27; 1p.
  - Acier, Marcel (Box 1)
    - To Boas [open letter], 1937 Oct. 25; 1p.
  - Ackermann, C.W. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 23; 1p.
  - Adam, Leonhard (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1919 Sept. 20; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 June 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Dec. 20; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1912 Dec. 15; 3p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Oct. 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1919 Nov. 6; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1923 Feb. 15; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1925 Dec. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1933 May 15; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Feb. 13; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 11; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 2; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1936 Feb. 26; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 11; (open letter)
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 21; 1p.
  - Adamic, Louis -- (et al) (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1939 July 8; 3p.
  - Adamowska, Antoinette S. (Mrs. Jos.) (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 12; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 10; 2p.
  - Adams, C.M. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1942 Nov. 16; 1p.
      (typed carbon signed by sec'y)
  - Adams, Comfort A. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 12; 1p.
      (typed carbon)
      (same to Brightman, E. Sharp, Malcolm)
  - Adams, Edward D. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1904 Jan. 25
    - From Boas, 1904 Feb. 2
    - From Boas, 1904 Feb. 10
    - From Boas, 1904 Feb. 16
    - From Boas, 1904 May 24
    - From Boas, 1904 Oct. 26
    - From Boas, 1905 Feb. 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Feb. 8; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Mar. 2
    - From Boas, 1905 May 8; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 June 3
    - From Boas, 1905 Oct. 19
    - From Boas, 1905 Oct. 24
    - (same to 5 others), 1905 Nov. 10; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Nov. 22
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 21; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1905 Dec. 26
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 20
    - From Boas, 1906 Jan. 31
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 3
    - From Boas, 1906 Mar. 9
    - From Boas, 1907 Apr. 30
    - From Boas, 1908 Sep. 3; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1908 Nov. 10
      - (see letter to Nicholas Murray Butler), 11/19/08
    - From Boas, 1910 Feb. 3; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1910 Apr. 28; 1p.
      (also sent to 3 others)
    - From Boas, 1911 May 3; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1911 May 6
    - From Boas, 1913 Feb. 5; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 14
    - From Boas, 1917 Mar. 12; 2p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 29; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1904 Oct. 27
    - To Boas, 1905 Feb. 3; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Feb. 9; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 May 9
    - To Boas, 1905 Oct. 23
    - To Boas, 1905 Dec. 7; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1905 Dec. 21
    - To Boas, 1906 Apr. 21
    - To Boas, 1906 Oct. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1906 Nov. 12; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1910 Feb. 2; 1p.
      (enc. missing)
    - To Boas, 1911 Feb. 23
    - To Boas, 1911 May 4
    - To Boas, 1920 Apr. 6; 1p.
  - Adams, E.E. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1928 Mar. 28; 1p.
  - Adams, E.G. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1928 May 1; 1p.
  - Adams Express Co. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1900 Mar. 19; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1913 Jan. 13; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1913 May 10; 1p.
      (all 3 above are receipts)
  - Adams, Gladys A. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1937 Sep. 10; 1p.
  - Adams, Helen S. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1939 Mar. 9; 1p.
  - Adams, Jos. T. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 4
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 18
    - To Boas, 1940 Feb. 16
    - To Boas, 1940 Mar. 31
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 30
    - To Boas, 1940 Nov. 6
  - Adams, Josephine T. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1940 Oct. 25; 1p.
    - From Boas (telegram), 1940 Nov. 31; 1p.
    - From Boas (3 cosigners), 1940 Apr. 30; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1940 Nov. 6; 1p.
  - Adams, Nicholson B. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1938 Jan.
  - Adams, N.P.G. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1936 Aug. 3; 1p.
  - Adams, Richard N. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1904 May 23
  - Adams, W.I. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1913 Oct.
  - Adamson, Thelma (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1927 Jun 7; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1928 Jun 1; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1932 Sep 26; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov 28; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 May 27; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1928 Jun 17; 2p.
    - To Boas, ? Dec.?
    - To Boas, 1929 Aug. 9; 9p.
    - To Boas, ? Dec.?
    - To Boas, 1930 Mar. 4; 2p.
    - D. Thomson -- to T. Adamson, Oct. 12, 1927
  - Addams, J. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1933 Oct. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Oct. 20; 1p
  - Adelman, Adrien (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1940 May 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 July10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 May 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 May 31; 1p
  - Adler, Carolyn (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1932 July 1; 2p
    - To Boas, 1932 July 12; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1932 Aug 20; 2p
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 4; 2p
    - To Boas, 1934 Sep. 21; 2p
    - To Boas, 1934 Oct. 28; 1p
  - Adler, C.M. (Box 1)
    - see Wright, E.H., 1931 Mar. 16
  - Adler, Cyrus (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1903 July29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1903 Aug. 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1903 Aug. 3; 5p
    - From Boas, 1906 Oct. 30
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Sep. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Dec. 31; 1p
    - From Boas, 1924 Dec. 31; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 Dec. 29; 2p
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Feb. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 13; 2p
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Mar. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 Feb. 4; 2p
    - From Boas, 1937 Mar. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Feb. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1938 Aug. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1899 Apr. 28
    - To Boas, 1903 July 31
    - To Boas, 1903 Aug. 6
    - To Boas, 1906 Sep. 20
    - To Boas, 1920 Sep. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Sep. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1921 Jan. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Jan. 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Mar. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Feb. 14; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 18; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Mar. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1937 Feb. 5; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1938 Oct. 12; 1p
    - Cyrus Adler -- to Waldman, M.D., 1938 July 18; 3p
    - Cyrus Adler -- to Warburg, F.M., 1924 Oct. 3; 1p
      - (enc. originally in C. Adler to Boas, 1925 Jan. 26)
  - Adler, Felix (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1904 Mar. 23; 3p
    - From Boas, 1914 Oct. 5
    - From Boas, 1917 May 19
    - From Boas, 1917 Nov. 2
    - From Boas, 1918 Sep. 9; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 Feb. 16; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 4; 2p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 17; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 26; 1p
    - From Boas, 1920 Mar. 29; 1p
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 9; 2p
    - To Boas, 1896 Mar. 30
    - To Boas, 1899 Apr. 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1899 July 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1908 Jan. 6
    - To Boas, 1918 Sept. 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 3; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Mar. 30; 1p
  - Alder, Herman M. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1924 Dec. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1925 Mar. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1924 Dec. 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1924 Dec. 10; 2p
    - To Boas, 1924 Dec. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1925 Jan. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1926 Dec. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Apr. 27; 1p
    - Alder -- to Bunzel, R.L., 1925 Feb. 27; 1p
  - Adler, Irving (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1933 Nov. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1933 Nov. 7; 1p
  - Adler, M. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1940 June 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1940 May 2; 1p
  - Adler, M.J. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1930 Dec. 18; 1p.
    - From Boas, 1931 Jan. 29; 1p.
    - To Boas, 1930 Dec. 11; 1p.
  - Affleck, G.B. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 20
    - From Boas, 1917 June 6
    - From Boas, 1919 Sep. 22; 3p.
    - From Boas, 1920 Apr. 9; 2p.
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 19
    - To Boas, 1917 Feb. 27
    - To Boas, 1917 June 8
    - To Boas (anthropometrical theses), 1917 Dec.?; 1p.
    - To Boss, 1919 Sep. 18; 1p.
    - To Boss, 1919 Oct. 1; 1p.
    - To Boss, 1920 Apr. 6; 1p.
  - Afro-American Institute (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1936 Feb. 27
      (see Branham, L.G. this date and enclosure)
  - Afros, John L. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1939 Jan. 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 Jan. 7; 1p
  - Agatston, Sigmund (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1930 Oct. 15; 1p
  - Aginsky, B.W. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1934 Aug. 20; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 14
    - To Boas (open letter), 1933 Dec. 29
    - To Boas, 1934 July 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1934 July 17; 2p
    - To Boas, 1934 Aug. 9; 3p
    - To Boas, 1934 Aug. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Aug. 24; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Sep. 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Dec. 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 29; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 June 2; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Sep. 12; 1p
    - Aginsky -- to Benedict, R.F., addressed to Dear Ruth, 1936 June 2; 2p.
  - Aginsky, Ethel G. (Box 1)
    - Nov. 11, 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Sep. 9; 1p
    - From Boas, 1935 Oct. 5; 2p
    - From Boas, 1935 Nov. 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Jan. 15; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Mar. 23; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 8; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Apr. 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 June19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Aug. 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Sep. 21; 1p
    - From Boas (open letter), 1941 Nov. 6
    - From Boas, 1942 Feb. 5; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Mar. 20; 1p
    - To Boas (open letter)
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec. 29
    - To Boas, 1935 July 1
    - To Boas, 1935 Aug. 13; 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 Sep. 9; 3p
    - To Boas, 1935 Oct. 1; 5p
    - To Boas, 1935 Oct. 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1935 Oct. 14; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Oct. 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1935 Dec. 9; 4p
    - To Boas, 1935 Nov. 24; 3p
    - To Boas, 1936 Jan. 10; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Feb. 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 Apr. 3; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 Apr. 15; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 Apr. 17; 2p
    - To Boas, 1936 May 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Aug. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Sept. 23; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Mar. 9; 1p
    - Aginsky -- from Bryan, R.W., 1935 Aug. 21
  - Agnew, A.M. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1913 Jan. 10
  - Agnew, J. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1924 Jan. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1924 Nov. 27; 1p
  - Aguayo, A. (Box 1)
    - Aguayo -- from Hernandez, E.A., 1925 Dec. 31
  - Ahrens, W. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 24; 1p
  - Aguerre, P. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1917 Jan. 19
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 11
    - From Boas, 1917 May 2
    - From Boas, 1917 May 22
  - Aichel, Otto (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1931 May 25; 1p
    - From Boas, 1932 Jan 28; 1p
    - From Boas, 1933 May 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 July 4; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Sep 7; card
    - To Boas, 1931 May 12; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Jan 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 July20; card
    - To Boas, 1933 Apr 16; 3p
  - Aiken, R.P. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug 31; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Sep 9; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Sep 16; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Sep 20; 1p
    - To Boas, 1916 Aug 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1916 Sep 16; 1p
  - Ainsworth, Dorothy S. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1930 July 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1930 June27; 1p
    - D. Ainsworth Sec'y, Jean Cormack -- to Boas, 1930 July 9; 1p
  - Aitken, R.T. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1915 Oct. 8
    - From Boas, 1915 Oct. 9
    - From Boas, 1916 Jan. 14
    - From Boas, 1916 Jan. 20
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 16
    - From Boas, 1917 June11
    - From Boas, 1917 Aug. 3
    - From Boas, 1917 Sept10
    - From Boas, 1917 Oct. 17
    - From Boas, 1918 Jan. 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1918 Jan. 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1921 May 2; 1p
    - From Boas, 1921 May 21; 1p
    - To Boas, 1915 Aug. 20
    - To Boas, 1915 Sep. 8
    - To Boas, 1915 Oct. 5
    - To Boas, 1915 Oct. 8
    - To Boas, 1915 Oct. 12
    - To Boas, 1915 Oct. 22
    - To Boas, 1915 Oct. 26
    - To Boas, 1915 Oct. 27
    - To Boas, 1915 Dec. 13
    - To Boas, 1916 Jan. 6
    - To Boas, 1916 Mar. 6
    - To Boas, 1916 July 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1916 July 31; 2p
    - To Boas, 1916 Aug. 5; 2p
    - To Boas, 1916 Sep. 18
    - To Boas, 1917 Jan. 18; 2p
    - To Boas, 1917 July 25
    - To Boas, 1917 July 29
    - To Boas, 1917 Sep. 13
    - To Boas, 1918 Jan. 9; 1p
      - (enc. orginally with Barnes, H.E., July 8, 1918), 1918 Apr. 15; 1p
    - To Boas, 1918 May 28; 1p
    - To Boas, 1921 Apr. 23; 2p
    - To Boas, 1921 Aug. 3; 2p
  - K. Akademie der Wiseenschaften München (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1912 Jan. 23
  - Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien (Box 1)
    - Certificate of F. Boas as member, 1923 May 29
    - From Haas, enc. Kerkhof, Franz, 1932 Aug. 9
  - Akers, W.G. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1934 Aug. 17; 1p
  - Al (Box 1)
    see Lesser, Alexander
  - Alba, G.H. de (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1936 Feb. 9; 1p
  - Albers, ----- (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1924 Sep. 2; 1p
  - Albert, J.J. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1914 Sep. 26
  - Alberts, A.S. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1939 Feb. 8; 1p
  - Aldrich, W.W. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1939 July 28; 1p
      - (enc. with Finkelstein, M.I. to Beard, C.A., 8-13-39)
  - "Alemania" (Box 1)
    - Bericht 1909-1910, 1910 May 1
  - Alesam, Friedrich (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1942 Mar. 7; 1p
  - Alexander, A.E. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1907 Dec. 27
  - Alexander, H. (Box 1)
    - To Frankfurter, F., 1918 July 6; 2p
      - (enc. with Grautoff, W. to Boas, F., 7-7-18)
  - Alexander, H.G. (Box 1)
    - See Boas, F. to Wright, E.H., 1931 Mar. 16
  - Alexander, M.C. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 7
    - To Boas, 1917 Apr. 17
  - Alexander, Will W. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1942 May 4; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 May 18; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 June 1; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Sep. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1942 Nov. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 May 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1942 Nov. 11; 1p
  - -------, Alice (Box 1)
    - 1907 Mar. 6, 2p
  - Alig & Baumgärtel (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1929 July 17; bill
    - To Boas, 1929 July 18; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 July 22; 1p
  - All Souls Universalist Church (Box 1)
    - (See Greenway, Cornelius, 7-16-36)
  - Alleman, M. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1917 Mar. 20
  - Allen,-------- (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1904 Dec. 16
    - To Boas, 1909 Mar. 26
  - Allen, A.W. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1932 July 15; 1p
  - Allen, Carolyn E. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1930 June 15; 1p
  - Allen, C.E. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1920 Aug. 7; 1p
    - To Boas, 1920 Aug. 16; 1p
  - Allen, Frederick M To Heuser, F.W.J. (Box 1)
    - 1923 Feb. 9, 1p
  - Allen, Grace (Box 1)
    - 1933 Mar. 1, 1p
  - Allen, Harrison (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1894 Jan. 29
    - To Boas, 1893 Oct. 9; 2p
    - To Boas, 1893 Dec. 13; 1p
    - To Boas, 1894 Jan. 26
  - Allen, J.A. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1900 Apr. 24; 2p
    - From Boas, 1901 Jan. 3; 1p
    - From Boas, 1915 Oct. 6
    - From Boas, 1917 Feb. 20
    - To Boas, 1915 Oct. 4
  - Allen, Jay (Box 1)
    - From Felon, E.I., 1937 Sep. 26
    - To Boas, 1938 Mar. 25; 2p
      - (enc. with Robison, Jay, 4-4-38)
    - From EfrC3n, D., 1938 May 5
  - Allen, Leroy H. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1932 Dec. 5; 1p
    - To Boas, 1932 Nov. 28; 1p
    - Allen, L. -- to Bloomfield L., 4-29-27
  - Allen, Leslie, H. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1923 Nov. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1923 Dec. 17; 1p
  - Allen, Louis (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 19; 1p
    - From Boas, 1928 Jan. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1929 Apr. 17; 1p
    - To Boas, 1928 Jan. 22; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Apr. 19; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 Apr. 26; 1p
    - To Boas, 1929 May 29; 1p
  - Allen, Martha (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1937 May 27; 1p
    - To Boas, 1937 May 26; 4p
  - Allen, Paul (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1940 Apr. 6; 1p
  - Alleter, G.F. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1898 Mar. 25; 1p
    - To Boas, 1898 Apr. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1898 May 17; 2p
  - Allgemeiner Deutscher Realschulmännerverein (Box 1)
    - (signature illegible: N. Sirneff?), 1922 Dec. 11; 2p
  - Allied Arts, Inc. (Box 1)
    - (see Benedek, T.A., 10-17-38)
  - Allison, W.J. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1936 Feb. 28; 1p
  - Allport, F.H. (Box 1)
    - To Lowie, 1913 Nov. 21
  - Allport, Gordon W. (Box 1)
    - see Boas, F. Open letter, Jan. '38
  - Allwood, L.V. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1935 Mar. 4; 1p
  - Alpers, Helene (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1910 Nov. 20; 1p
  - Alphandéry, ----- (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1923 Feb. 20; 1p
  - Alsberg, Henry G. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1933 Mar 28; 3p
    - From Boas, 1936 Mar. 10; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 Mar. 14; 1p
    - From Boas, 1936 June 11; 1p
    - From Boas, 1937 May 6; 1p
  - Alsberg, H.G. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1936 Mar. 13; 1p
  - Altamira, Rafael (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1910 June 25
    - From Boas, 1924 Sep. 8; 1p
    - To Boas, 1924 Nov. 3; 1p
  - Altborn, E. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1917 Apr. 3
  - Althoff, F. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1905 Feb. 24; 1p
    - From Boas, 1907 July; 18p
    - From Boas, 1907 July 7; 1p
    - From Boas, 1907 July 9; 2p
    - To Boas, 1907 July 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1907 July 17; 1p
  - Altieri, R.A. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1939 Apr. 1; 1p
    - To Boas, 1939 June 3; 1p
  - Altman, S. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1910 Dec. 15
  - Altschul, A. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1933 Dec.(?); 1p
  - Amador, M. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1912 Mar. 20
      (not in file)
  - Ambronn, Hermann (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1923 Mar. 6; 1p
    - To Boas, 1927 Jan. 13; 2p
    - To Boas, 1927 Feb. 6; 4p
  - Ambrosetti, J.B. (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1903 Dec. 14; 2p
  - Amend, Otto (Box 1)
    - To Boas (E.L.), 1904 June 23; 1p
  - Ament, C.B. (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1934 Jan. 11; 1p
    - To Boas, 1934 Jan. 3; 2p
  - American (Box 1)
    - To Boas, 1937 Sep. 9; 1p
  - American Anthropological Association (Box 1)
    - From Boas, 1937 Apr. 13
    - Transcript, 1913 Jan.
    - From Holmes, 1919 Sep. 12; 1p
    - From Boas, 1919 Dec. 29; 2p
    - From Wissler, 1920 Nov. 5; 3p
    - From Wissler, 1921 Nov. 15; 5p
    - Report, 1926 Feb. 24
    - Agenda, 1937 Apr. 25
    - Proceedings, Ling., 1937 Apr. 25-26; 39p
    - Resolutions Ling., 1937 Apr. 25; 3p
    - Resolutions Ling., 1939 Jan. 13; 1p
  - American Anthropologist (Box 1)
    - See also Goddard, Pliny E. Spier, Leslie, 5-6-36
    - See also Goddard, Pliny E. Spier, Leslie, 5-13-36
    - See also Goddard, Pliny E. Spier, Leslie, 5-18-36
  - American Architect (Box 1)
    See Cricker, William H. Howard, William E.
  - Am. Assn. for Advancement of Physical Education (Box 2)
    - Member. certif., 1897 May 8
    - To Boas from Savage, W.L., 1901 Dec. 15; 1p
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 2)
    - To Boas from E.S. Morse, President, 1886 Aug. 24
    - ?, 1887 Aug. 16
    - Minutes, 1898 Feb. 18; 3p
    - Report, 1898 Dec. 28; 2p
    - To Boas from M. Benjamin, Sec'y, 1902 Nov. 19; 1p
    - From Boas to Hrdlicka, A., 1919 Mar. 13
    - See Pupin, M.I., 1925 Oct. 6
    - Resolution, 1926 Mar. 14
    - Resolution, 1930 Dec. 31; 1p
    - Minutes,Council, 1930 Dec. 29-31; 5p
    - Minutes,Council, 1931 Jan. 1; 3p
    - Proceedings, 1930
      - (see True, R.H., 1-26-31)
    - Minutes, Exec., 1931 Jan. 1; 5p
    - List, Officers, 1931? Apr.?; 1p
    - Resolutions, 1931 Jan. 1; 4p
    - Proposal, 1931 Jan. 1
    - Minutes, Exec., 1931 Apr. 25-26; 3p
    - See Roos, C.F., 1931 Sep. 25
    - ? A.A.A.S. File, 1931 Dec. 16; 1p
    - Sec'ies Conf., 1931 Dec.; 10p
    - Programs, 1931 Dec.; 2p
      Also see Krogman, Wilton Marion Livingston, Burton E.
  - American Association for International Conciliation (Box 2)
    - From Boas, 1914 Nov. 2
  - American Assn. of Physical Anthropologists (Box 2)
    - Constitution, 1924 Dec. 16
      (enc. in Hrdlicka, A.)
  - American Assn. of Scientific Workers, N.Y. (Box 2)
    - 1939 Feb.?, ? 1p
  - American Assn. of University Professors (Box 2)
    - Resolution, 1933 Dec.?; ? 4cc
  - American Breeders Assn, Eugenic Sec., Immigration Committee (Box 2)
    - 1st Report, 1911 Dec. 30; 7p
  - American Chemical Society (Box 2)
    See Parsons, Charles L.
  - American Civil Liberties Union, Comm. on Indian Civil Rights (Box 2)
    - Minutes, 1931 Apr. 1; 1p
    - Civil rights, 1932 May; 4p
    - From Ward, Harry F, 1940 Mar. 18
      (enc. with Ward, Muriel)
  - American Colonial Bank of Porto Rico (Box 2)
    - From Boas, 1915 July 9